# JAMES "COURTNEY" PERIGO

## EXPERT DATA SCIENCE LEADER DRIVING INNOVATION FOR BUSINESS SUCCESS.

## **CONTACT**

linkedin.com/in/ courtneyperigo/ courtneyperigo.com github.com/ agentdanger courtneyperigo.medium.com

## **SKILLS**

Applied Data Science
Data Engineering
AI and ML Deployment
Business Intel Architecture
Cloud Infrastructure
Python, R, SQL, Go, JS
Servant Leadership

## **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University **MS, Data Science** 2020-2022

Univ of South Florida

MBA, Finance & Marketing

2007-2009

Univ of South Florida BA, Advertising 1998-2003

### **PROFILE**

Data science leader and practitioner with over 15 years of experience turning data into insights that drive ROI. An innovator, building proprietary solutions that use machine learning and data engineering to generate millions in value for business. My goal is to affect operations, sales, and marketing through innovative, powerful, and scaled decision analytics product.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

SVP, Executive Director of Marketing and Data Sciences

## Cramer-Krasselt | 2021 - present

Lead the agency's global data science and analytics capabilities with an integrated team across three offices. Build data products, architect analytics microservices, and develop data-driven models for marketing optimization and personalization – creating \$5MM+ in annual recurring revenue for the agency. Won the Drum Digital Advertising Award for our novel curve-fit optimization model for marketing attribution.

SVP, Director of Data Strategy and Utilization

### Cramer-Krasselt | 2018 - 2021

Re-aligned an analytics team, and the tech stack, for an agile analytics approach progressing the agency through a digital transformation for shared intelligence across finance, operations and delivery. Built a predictive benchmarking capability that automates analysis for C-K's performance marketing teams – generating a consistent 5-10% increase in paid marketing performance.

VP, Director of Decision Sciences

## Publicis, Moxie | 2014 - 2018

Recruited and developed top analytics and data science talent to serve the agency's largest accounts including eBay, Kohl's, and Verizon Wireless. Engineered a real-time Hidden Markov Model that estimates the position of a prospect in the sales funnel for Verizon Wireless. Won a Golden Echo Award for Best Use of Data.

## JAMES "COURTNEY" PERIGO

## EXPERT DATA SCIENCE LEADER DRIVING INNOVATION FOR BUSINESS SUCCESS

### **EXPERIENCE, CONTINUED**

Director, Analytics

## Triad Retail Media, Wal-Mart | 2012 - 2014

Streamlined reporting and business intelligence, reducing report turnaround times from three days to on-demand by implementing Tableau and a PostgreSQL Data Warehouse in support of the sales department. Helped @WalmartLabs in the development of attribution solutions that link credit card transactions to omni-channel shopper marketing efforts – helping companies like P&G and Pepsi understand the ROI of their retail marketing efforts.

Market Research Manager, Mobile Healthcare Solutions

## Sage Software | 2010 - 2012

Developed the product roadmap for the company's first mobile electronic health records solution for ambulatory care practices. Curated the backlog of product features for software developers, helping the team focus on key features suggested from conjoint-analysis and pricing exercises in primary market research and survey analyses.

Manager, Analytics

## Triad Retail Media, Wal-Mart | 2009 - 2010

Built the processes for business intelligence for the start-up, helping the sales team achieve \$200 million in annual billings.

Sr. Marketing Analyst

## Media General, The Tampa Tribune | 2005 - 2009

Conducted statistical analysis, and developed data visualizations in support of news and sales teams with emphasis on geographic information systems and mapping.

Media Planner, Buyer

Doner Advertising, FKQ Advertising | 2003 - 2005

### **PUBLICATIONS**

"Get More Out of Your Data with Analytics Microservices"

## Towards Data Science | 2022

https://towardsdatascience.com/get-more-out-of-your-data-with-analytics-microservices-9a5a34a3ad2f

"Risk Assessment of Daily Fantasy Baseball Games Using Monte Carlo Analysis"

## HackerNoon, MLearning.ai | 2022

https://hackernoon.com/using-monte-carlo-simulation-to-determine-why-you-wont-win-daily-fantasy-baseball-games